<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.richthibault.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.richthibault.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-08-29T23:35:24-04:00</updated><id>http://www.richthibault.com/</id><title>Rich Thibault</title><subtitle>Java and Mobile Developer</subtitle><entry><title>LinkThrow is Now Live!</title><link href="http://www.richthibault.com/LinkThrow-is-now-live/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="LinkThrow is Now Live!" /><published>2016-08-28T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-08-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.richthibault.com/LinkThrow-is-now-live</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.richthibault.com/LinkThrow-is-now-live/">&lt;p&gt;I often find myself reading some long web page on my Mac, and wishing I had an easy way to
“throw” it over to my iPhone so I could continue reading on the go. Emailing the link to 
myself was one way to handle it - and with the Messages app, I could “text” the link to myself - but I always wished there was an easier way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple’s Handoff functionality is great, but you have to be using Safari - and, well, I prefer Google Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when I saw the linkthrow.com domain was available, I snatched it up!  And then…sat on it for three years without doing anything.  But I finally set aside a couple weekends to work on it, and the site is now live: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkthrow.com&quot;&gt;LinkThrow.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It only works with Chrome and iOS right now, but I’ll probably build an Android app and some more browser extensions if there’s any demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Install the extension for Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Install the mobile app on your iPhone or iPad - be sure to choose Yes when asked if you want to receive push notifications.  It won’t work otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The mobile app will give you a six-character code - enter that code in the browser extension and you can start throwing links.  Throwing a link to the phone sends a push notification, and sliding to open the push notification launches the page in mobile Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-i-learned&quot;&gt;What I learned&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was also a learning exercise for me.  I hadn’t had much opportunity to play around with MongoDB, so I’m using that for the back end.  Spring Data made it very simple to integrate with the app.  I did find Mongo’s security a bit confusing - I somehow ended locking myself out of my own database!  I finally decided to leave “auth” disabled and just block outside access at the network level, using Amazon’s VPC permissions.  Easy enough to just tunnel in if I need to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had never done a Chrome extension before, so that was a first.  It’s basically just a block of HTML with some Javascript to handle the Ajax calls.  What’s nice is once I add my iPhone on one Mac, I can throw to it from all my Macs, since extensions are tied to your Google account and shared across all devices.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="LinkThrow" /><category term="MongoDB" /><category term="Chrome" /><summary>I often find myself reading some long web page on my Mac, and wishing I had an easy way to
“throw” it over to my iPhone so I could continue reading on the go. Emailing the link to 
myself was one way to handle it - and with the Messages app, I could “text” the link to myself - but I always wished there was an easier way.</summary></entry><entry><title>Hello, whirled.</title><link href="http://www.richthibault.com/Hello-World/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, whirled." /><published>2016-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2016-08-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.richthibault.com/Hello-World</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.richthibault.com/Hello-World/">&lt;p&gt;BREAKING NEWS - Web developer takes 20 years to get around to making his own website.  Film at 11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never too late right?  I’ll use this space mostly to talk about web development, especially Java and Spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and here’s the obligatory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HELLO WORLD&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary>BREAKING NEWS - Web developer takes 20 years to get around to making his own website.  Film at 11.</summary></entry></feed>
